<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Partially Random</title>
    <link>/categories/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Partially Random</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Partially Random</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is to be rational?</title>
      <link>/2018/10/23/2018-10-23-what-is-to-be-rational/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</author>
      <guid>/2018/10/23/2018-10-23-what-is-to-be-rational/</guid>
      <description>This afternoon I was reading a book about rationality in voting behavior called “An economic theory of political action in a democracy”(Downs 1957). An amazing work (so far), for sure I do not discard that it’s likely I’ve a biased position regarding the application and precision of rational models in economics. However, what impressed me was authors’ self-awareness of the underlying flaws behind rational analysis in decision making, and not covering them like they do not exist in a book from 1957!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to cope with the media bias in the news market?</title>
      <link>/2018/09/04/2018-09-04-should-we-demand-mess-media-bias-or-diverge-our-information-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</author>
      <guid>/2018/09/04/2018-09-04-should-we-demand-mess-media-bias-or-diverge-our-information-sources/</guid>
      <description>In the new age of information, the common wisdom dictates that people acquire and validate cues that endorse their prejudices. Nonetheless, it is likely that information providers were aware of such behavior even from the times when the print press was invented, taking advance to maximize the probability of inflicting influence in the society.
In an Economic theory on demand for news assumes that individuals read, watch and listen to information according to a function that maximizes the utility for given better decision-making function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>