<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Decision Making on Partially Random</title>
    <link>/tags/decision-making/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Decision Making on Partially Random</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</webMaster>
    <copyright>(c) 2018 Copyright Partially Random</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/decision-making/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to cope with the media bias in the news market?</title>
      <link>/2018/09/04/2018-09-04-should-we-demand-mess-media-bias-or-diverge-our-information-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</author>
      <guid>/2018/09/04/2018-09-04-should-we-demand-mess-media-bias-or-diverge-our-information-sources/</guid>
      <description>In the new age of information, the common wisdom dictates that people acquire and validate cues that endorse their prejudices. Nonetheless, it is likely that information providers were aware of such behavior even from the times when the print press was invented, taking advance to maximize the probability of inflicting influence in the society.
In an Economic theory on demand for news assumes that individuals read, watch and listen to information according to a function that maximizes the utility for given better decision-making function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What motives us?</title>
      <link>/2018/09/04/2018-09-04-what-motives-us/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</author>
      <guid>/2018/09/04/2018-09-04-what-motives-us/</guid>
      <description>I listened this podcast yesterday morning, better than breakfast… Well almost as good, they’re actually more like complementary goods. 😅 😅</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incertidumbre y otros cuentos: Entre los Alvarados ¿cuál es mejor apuesta?</title>
      <link>/2018/03/25/2018-03-25-incertidumbre-y-otros-cuentos-entre-los-alvarados-cu%C3%A1l-es-mejor-apuesta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</author>
      <guid>/2018/03/25/2018-03-25-incertidumbre-y-otros-cuentos-entre-los-alvarados-cu%C3%A1l-es-mejor-apuesta/</guid>
      <description>Estamos a una semana de saber cuál candidato nos va a gobernar por los siguientes cuatro años, y existe en mí un revuelo de ideas sobre qué pasará, y que hace muy difícil tomar la decisión sobre si Carlos o Fabricio Alvarado (CAQ y FAM desde ahora) lo harán mejor. Este post es un intento de formalizar conceptos y ayudar al votante a que tome la decisión más coherente posible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayes y el cajero automático</title>
      <link>/2018/02/23/2018-02-23-bayes-y-el-cajero-autom%C3%A1tico/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>opoyserc@gmail.com (Obryan Poyser)</author>
      <guid>/2018/02/23/2018-02-23-bayes-y-el-cajero-autom%C3%A1tico/</guid>
      <description>Hace unos años cuando cursaba el grado en economía en la Universidad Nacional me llamó mucho la atención un fenómeno recurrente en las personas que sacan dinero en los ATM y que ahora tiene mucho más sentido.
En ese entonces había un par de cajeros automáticos del Banco Nacional cerca de la oficina de registro, desconozco si aún estarán allí. Era normal que hubiera una fila de al menos 10 personas esperando su turno.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>